Gerardo Andrés Mazzei Capote

45 N. Randall Ave, Apt. 109 • Madison, WI- 53715 (608) 622-4643 • mazzeicapote@wisc.edu linkedin.com/in/gerardo-mazzei-capote

SUMMARY

Mechanical engineer with a minor in business. Experienced in polymer-based additive manufacturing technologies and polymer processing. Highly skilled in thermal analysis and mechanical testing of polymers, as well as composite theory and failure criteria. Versatile communicator.

EDUCATION

- University of Wisconsin-Madison Madison, WI, U.S.A.
 - **PhD**: Mechanical Engineering 2018 present (Expected August 2021)
 - MSc: Mechanical Engineering 2016 2018.
- Universidad Simón Bolívar Caracas, Venezuela
 - **BSc**: Materials Engineering 2009 2016.

ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

PhD Candidate

under Prof. Tim Osswald, UW-Madison

August 2016 - Present

- Extruded an ABS FFF filament with tight dimensional tolerances to achieve high precision volumetric output during 3D printing.
- Offered expertise in the design of topological crystal insulators to be manufactured through Additive Manufacturing techniques.
- Manufactured a cost-effective heat exchanger using metal filled conductive thermoplastic materials.
- Designed and manufactured a low-cost, thermoformed reusable N9X mask during the COVID19 pandemic.
- Developed a failure surface for FFF parts using careful design of experiments based on statistics and mechanics of materials.
- Developed and produced 3D printed coupons with unusual bead orientations using a customized 6-axis robotic printer.

SKILLS

Polymer processing techniques: Extrusion, Injection Molding, FDM/FFF, SLS, DLS **Analysis techniques**: TGA, DSC, LFA, DMA, Destructive Mechanical Testing, μ CT

Programming languages: MATLAB, Python, R, RAPID, G-code **Engineering software**: Solidworks, EES, Origin, Jupyter Notebooks

Other software: Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Animate

Languages: English, Spanish, Portuguese

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant University of Wisconsin-Madison **August 2017 - Present** Responsible for the instruction and grading of 'ME370 - Energy Systems Lab', 'ME514 - Additive Manufacturing', and 'ME418 - Engineering Design with Polymers', all offered by the Mechanical Engineering Department. Consistently received high ratings from students.

Vice President Society of Plastic Engineers - Madison Chapter **August 2018- May 2020** Coordinated industry visits and outreach activities aimed at increasing the interest of engineering students in the field of polymer processing.

Gerardo Andrés Mazzei Capote

Resume – page 2

TECHNICAL PRESENTATIONS

AMUG Chicago, IL 2019

• A Novel Failure Criterion Applied for Fused Filament Fabrication Parts.

RAPID Fort Worth, TX 2018

• A Tensor Based Failure Criterion for FFF Manufactured Parts.

SFF Austin, TX 2017

• Towards a Robust Production of FFF End-User Parts with Improved Tensile Properties.

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. T Pfeifer et al. "Optimization of the FDM™ additive manufacturing process". In: 74th Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition of the Society of Plastics Engineers, Indianapolis 2016 (2016), pp. 22–26. URL: https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85010644519{\&}partnerID=40{\&}md5=1f4521e160fe433ad37ef9bb587ee72e
- 2. Gerardo A. Mazzei Capote et al. "Towards a Robust Production of FFF End-User Parts with Improved Tensile Properties". In: *Proceedings of the 28th Annual International Solid Freeform Fabrication Symposium An Additive Manufacturing Conference*. Austin, TX, 2017, pp. 507–518
- 3. Gerardo A. Mazzei Capote et al. "Failure surface development for ABS fused filament fabrication parts". In: *Additive Manufacturing* 28.April (2019), pp. 169–175. ISSN: 22148604. DOI: 10.1016/j.addma.2019.05.005. URL: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addma.2019.05.005
- 4. J.L. Colón Quintana et al. "Viscoelastic properties of fused filament fabrication parts". In: *Additive Manufacturing* 28 (2019). ISSN: 22148604. DOI: 10.1016/j.addma.2019.06.003
- 5. Gerardo A. Mazzei Capote, Alec Redmann, and Tim A. Osswald. "Validating a Failure Surface Developed for ABS Fused Filament Fabrication Parts through Complex Loading Experiments". In: *Journal of Composites Science* 3.2 (2019). DOI: https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs3020049
- 6. P. V. Osswald et al. "Failure Criterion for PA 12 Multi-Jet Fusion Additive Manufactured Parts". In: Additive Manufacturing July (2020), p. 101668. ISSN: 2214-8604. DOI: 10.1016/j.addma.2020.101668. URL: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addma.2020.101668

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Venezuelan and Italian citizenship.
- Holder of Brazilian permanent resident visa.
- Exchange student through the Rotary Youth Exchange Program (August 2008 to June 2009).